Guide to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Western Conference records 1948-2008 IBT0025
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Western Conference Records
1940-2008
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
International Brotherhood of Teamsters
IBT0025
3.5 Linear Feet
This collection contains correspondence, meeting minutes, legal documents, financial records, programs, pamphlets, and reports. The material dates from 1940-2008. These are the records of the Western Conference of Teamsters, a regional governance body in the structure of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters.
Arrangement
Organized into 5 series: Records, Agreement, History, Publication - Pamphlets - Materials; and Proceedings
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence, meeting minutes, legal documents, financial records, programs, pamphlets, and reports. The material dates from 1948-2008. These are the records of the Western Conference of Teamsters, a regional governance body in the structure of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters.
Biographical / Historical
Within the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, between 1937 and 1995, members of the union met and exchanged ideas on a regional basis. These regional organizations were called Area Conferences. In the U.S. there were four area Area Conferences: the Western Conference of Teamsters formed in 1937, the Southern Conference of Teamsters formed in 1944, the Central States Conference of Teamsters formed in 1953, and the Eastern Conference of Teamsters also formed in 1953. Canadian Teamsters had their own Canadian Conference of Teamsters, known today as Teamsters Canada. Area Conferences met annually to discuss general issues facing the IBT and to hold discussion more directly relevant to IBT Trade Divisions: contract negotiations, organizing campaigns, workplace disputes, etc. For example, when the Central States Conference met, after the general sessions, delegates would meet based on the trades they represented: the brewery and soft drink delegates coming together, cannery delegates coming together, dairy delegates coming together, etc. In this way, the IBT was strengthened in terms of both national and regional coordination of efforts. The Area Conferences came under criticism during the General Presidency of Ron Carey. Making the argument that they were redundant and wasteful, Carey disbanded them in 1995.
Conferences; Labor; Labor unions; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century
- Records, 1948-1977; Series 1; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the reports of the Western Conference of Teamsters from 1948-1977 and includes annual divisional reports pertaining to the everyday operation of the Eastern Conference.
  - "A Report From ... " Western Conference of Teamsters, 1968-1970; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Report of the International Director, 12 September 1977; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Report of the Proceedings 12th Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 28 June - 2 July 1948; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Report of the Proceedings 13th Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 24-29 October 1949; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Report of the Proceedings 21st Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 24-28 June 1957; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Report of the Proceedings 23rd Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 7-10 July 1959; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Report of the Proceedings 24th Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, October 1961; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Report of the Proceedings 25th Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, July 1963; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Report of the Proceedings 26th Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, July 1965; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Report of the Proceedings 29th Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, November 1971; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Agreements, 1958-1961; Series 2; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains the administrative files of the Western Conference of Teamsters from 1958-1961 and includes the master frieght agreements.
  - Eleven Western States Master Frieght Agreement, 1958-1961; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- History, 1942, 1950; Series 3; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains the administrative files of the Western Conference of Teamsters and includes the history of the Conference.
  - History Of The Western Conference of Teamsters, Undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - John P. McLauglin Identity Card, 1942; IBT0025 Series 3 (Box SHARED Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Obituary for John P. McLaughlin, 1950; IBT0025 Series 3 (Box SHARED Box 31, Folder 7)
- Publications - Pamphlets - Materials, 1955 - 2008; Series 4; 1.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains the administrative files of the Western Conference of Teamsters from 1970-2008 and includes pamphlets, summaries, and publications from the Conference
  - Western Conference of Teamsters Organizing Manual for Hospitals, 1975; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Western Conference of Teamsters Organizing Materials, Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Western Conference of Teamsters Over the Road Division Contract Summaries, 1955; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Western Conference of Teamsters Pension Plan - Summary Plan Booklet, 2008; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Western Conference of Teamsters Summary of Legal Plan, 2005; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Western Conference of Teamsters - Teamsters Progress: An Address By President David Beck, Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Western Conference of Teamsters "The Right To Work ... Talking it Over", Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Western Region Meeting, 31 March - 4 April 2001; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Western Region Meeting, 28-29 June 1999; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Workshop, January 1968; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Workshop, January 1968; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Workshop, October 1972; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Workshop on Pensions, Health, and Welfare Programs, 26 - 30 April 1978; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Twenty-Sixth Western Conference of Teamsters, July 1965; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Workshop, January 1968; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Workshop on Pensions, Health, and Welfare Programs, 26 April - 30 April, 1970; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Twenty-Ninth Western Conference of Teamsters, November 1971; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Western Conference of Temsters' Workshop, October 1972; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - History of Western Conference of Teamsters, ND; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Proceedings, 1940 - 1949; Series 5; 1.5 Linear Feet
  Arranged chronologically
  This series contains the proceedings of the Western Conference of Teamsters from 1940-1948
  - Proceedings of the 5th Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 1-4 September 1940; Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings of the 6th Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 1-3 October 1941; Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Proceedings of the 7th Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 1-5 June 1942; Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Proceedings of the 8th Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 6-11 June 1943; Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Proceedings of the 9th Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 14-18 August 1944; Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Proceedings of the 10th Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 1-6 April 1946; Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Proceedings of the 11th Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 4-10 May 1949; Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Report of the Proceedings of the Seventh Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 1 June - 5 June, 1942; Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Report of the Proceedings of the Eighth Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 6 June - 11 june, 1943; Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Report of the Proceedings of the Ninth Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 14 August - 18 august, 1944; Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Report of the Proceedings of the Ninth Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters (Copy), 14 August - 18 August, 1944; Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Report of the Proceedings of the Tenth Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 1 April - 6 April, 1946; Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Report of the Proceedings of the Eleventh Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 4 May - 10 May, 1947; Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Report of the Proceedings of the Thirteenth Meeting of the Western Conference of Teamsters, 24 October - 29 October, 1949; Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 8)